foreign
testing now in all the previous sessions
we have already seen how you can work
with API testing in Tosca using API scan
and also the Tosca Commander to create
API test cases and also verify your apis
but today uh we are going to look at
some of the different options which are
now available especially on the
authentication side right so we have
looked at some of the authentication
mechanisms which are available in Tosca
but today I'm going to show you with
specific examples on how you can use
this authentication types okay
so the authentication type which is the
basic one or the first you can say also
is the basic authentication right and as
the name suggests this uh authentication
is used for apis where you have to pass
a username and password before you can
authenticate a particular request okay
so for this purpose
um I'm going to create a API message
okay I have already created a folder you
can see authentication and then this is
the new message okay I'm going to name
it basic uh auth okay
and then
um in this end point I'm going to use a
particular API message okay and for this
purpose I'm going to use one of the
sample apis or provided by Postman and
this is to test the basic Authentication
obviously you can use any API okay where
you need a basic authentication which is
basically a username and password okay
any API which is protected by a username
and password you can use that endpoint
but I'm going to use this particular
endpoint so it is called Postman eco
.com and slash basic auth
okay so I'm going to use this particular
endpoint and then let's first check
whether we get any response back when we
send this without any authentication
okay let's see whether it is protected
or not
so let's try and run this and let's see
what is the response for this particular
request okay
so it's expected uh I'm getting a 401
unauthorized right for status code and
in the payload I'm getting unauthorized
which means I'm not authorized to
basically access this particular API
right and I need to provide uh some
authentication which should be present
in the request okay and it will be sent
back to the server so that it can
authorize that particular request and
then send the response back okay
so now let's go back to the request and
this time around let's try with
authentication basic okay you will find
it here
and in the username and password so I'm
going to pass the username and the
password
okay so uh
now we have provided the authentication
now let's go ahead and run this again
once more and let's see whether this
time around it can authorize this
particular request okay
so as you can see this time around uh
the status quote was 200 okay and also
we got a response uh payload which is
authenticated true okay
so this way you can use the basic
authentication in Tosca API scan to
authenticate your requests using a
username and password
so this is one of the most common uh
authentication mechanisms used for apis
right and then there are other API
messages which you different types of
authentication mechanisms okay
so in the next session I'm going to also
show you how you can use another
authentication type and which is the
digest Authentication
okay
so that's all for this session hope it
was useful and you learned something new
so in the next session as I said I will
be talking about another authentication
type which is digest authentication so
do tune into our channel to watch the
new video and if you're not subscribed
then do subscribe so that you get
notified whenever I add this particular
video Until then keep watching and keep
learning